So, here's an interesting observation.
所以这是个有趣的观察
In order to minimize the mean squared error,
为了最小化均方误差
we do not actually need to use gradient descent or the tricks.
我们实际上不需要梯度下降法或技巧
We can actually do this in a closed mathematical form. Let me show you.
我们可以在封闭的数学形式中完成 让我来展示一下
Here's our data, (X1,Y1) all the way to (xm,ym) and in this case m is 5.
这是我们的数据 (X1,Y1) 直到 (Xm,Ym) 在这个例子中 m 为 5
And the areas of the squares represent our squared error.
这些正方形区域代表了我们的平方误差
So, our input is point X1 up to point xm and our labels are Y1 up to ym,
所以我们输入点 X1 直到 Xm 标签为 Y1 直到 Ym
and our predictions are of the form,
我们预测的形式是
Yi hat equals w_1x_i plus w2, where
Yi-hat = W1 Xi + W2
w_1 is a slope of the line and w_2 is the Y intercept.
W1 是直线的斜率 W2 是 y 轴截距
And the mean squared error is given by this formula over here.
通过这个公式得到均方误差是这样的
Notice that I've written the error as a function of w_1
注意这里我写的误差为函数 W1
and w_2 since given any w_1 and w_2,
和 W2 因为给定了任何 W1 和 W2
we can calculate the predictions and the error based on these values of w_1 and w_2.
我们可以根据 W1 和 W2 计算预测和误差
Now, as we know from calculus,
现在既然了解了微积分
in order to minimize this error,
为了最小化误差
we need to take the derivatives with respect to the two input variables,
我们需要根据两个输入变量 W1 和 W2 求导
w_1 and w_2, and set them both equal to zero.
将两个都设为 0
We calculate the derivatives,
我们计算导数
and you can see the full calculation in the instructor notes,
你可以在教学笔记里看到整个运算
and we get these two formulas.
并且我们得到这两个公式
And now we just need to solve for w_1 and w_2 for these two equations to be zero.
现在我们只需要解决 W1 和 W2 为 0 的两个方程
So, what do we have now?
那么我们现在得到什么呢？
We have a system of two equations and two unknowns.
我们得到二元方程组 含有两个未知数
We can easily solve this using linear algebra.
我们可以使用线性代数很容易地解决这个问题
So, another question is,
所以另一个问题是
why don't we do this all the time?
为什么不能总是这样做？
Why do we have to go through many gradient descent steps instead of just
为什么我们需要通过梯度下降法
solving a system of equations and unknowns? Well, think about this.
而不是只对含有未知数的方程组求解呢？ 这样来考虑一下
If you didn't have only two dimensions in the input but you have n,
如果你输入的不是只有两个维度 而是有 n 个
then you would have n equations with n unknowns.
那么就会得到含有 n 个未知数的 n 元方程组
And solving a system of n equations with n unknowns is very expensive,
对含有 n 个未知数的 n 元方程组求解非常费力
because if n is big,
因为如果 n 很大
then at some point of our solution,
那么在某个点上的解
we have to invert an n by n matrix.
我们需要转置一个 n*n 的矩阵
Inverting a huge matrix is something that
转置大矩阵
takes a lot of time and a lot of computing power.
会耗费大量时间和计算能力
So, this is simply not feasible.
所以这并不可行
So instead, this is why we use gradient descent.
因此这就是我们使用梯度下降法的原因
It will not give us the exact answer necessarily,
这种方法不能给出准确答案
but it will get us pretty close to
但是可以让我们无限接近
the best answer which will give us a solution that fits our data pretty well.
最佳答案 给我们较好拟合数据的解答
But if we had infinite computing power,
但是如果我们具有无限的计算能力
we would just solve the system and solve linear regression in one
我们可以解决方程组 用一个步骤解决线性回归